Jordan Hudson





SUMMARY

Self-motivated, innovative thought-leader with proven technical and business acumen and talent for problem solving. Over five years of experience working with code throughout high school and college, as well as over one year of technical experience in my most recent roles as a senior analyst for Accenture and a Freelance Software Engineer. Passion for creating fully functional yet beautiful web/mobile applications; but also open to learning other technologies and tackling new challenges that come my way.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SELF-EMPLOYED

SEATTLE, WA 4/2018-Current

Software Engineer

CHOREGANIZER (https://github.com/Jordaness/choreganizer)

Java/Spring Boot based chore organization full-stack web application

Technology: Tomcat/Apache, Spring Boot, Java (Backend), JavaScript (Frontend),

Hibernate, MySQL, jQuery, Bootstrap 4

Contributions: Implemented landing page with a visually dynamic interactive graphical background built in pure CSS and vanilla JavaScript. Also, constructed a backend API supported with jQuery based front-end for landing/dashboard pages, reducing page refresh by 45%, as well as modernizing the user experience and decreasing server load.

WIZARDS GAME (https://github.com/Jordaness/wizards)

MEAN based multiplayer card game full-stack web application

Technology: Node.JS, Express, Redux, Socket.io, Angular 6, JavaScript, TypeScript, SASS Contributions: Designed, architected, and engineered a reusable modularized combat API system based in Angular 6 for handling core gameplay functionality. As well as, constructed SASS based UI/UX for displaying game state. Additionally, refined Redux reducer/actions and Socket.io broadcast logic for game state mutation.

ACCENTURE LLC. SEATTLE, WA **Senior Analyst** 5/2016-4/2018

- Led the design and development of process improvement tool that successfully automated an manual process, reducing cycle time by over 70%
- Built and managed a database reporting system using Microsoft's Excel and Power BI, leading to an increase in segment performance by 60%
- Managed process governance and created tracking tools using Microsoft's SharePoint and Power BI for all process changes, providing better client insight for change proposals
- Maintained full-stack automation solution of SQL Server/C#/ASP.Net, managing daily execution and performance reporting in Power BI, and creating process documentation

COSTCO WHOLESALE INC.

ISSAQUAH, WA 5/2015-5/2016

Financial Analyst

• Partnered with teams across Costco providing financial analysis for processes such as budgeting and forecasting.

Inventory Control Specialist

1/2015-5/2015

• Reviewed department inventory reports weekly and tracked item replenishment and purchase orders. Sent and tracked vendor contracts, and ad/logo agreements.

EDUCATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES

JavaScript

TypeScript

Python

Java

Dart

VBA

HTML

CSS

SASS

FRAMEWORKS/TOOLS

Angular

Express

Node.JS

Django

Flask

Spring boot

JQuery

Bootstrap

Socket.io

Redux

Tomcat

Mongoose

AWS EC2 Git/GitHub

MVC/MVVC

Flutter (Android/iOS)

DATABASES

MySQL

SQL Lite

SQL Server MongoDB

Firebase